var questions = [
    {
        "question": "The following are characteristics of a project except:",
        "option1" : "It is a temporary in nature",
        "option2": "It is continuous",
        "option3": "It is unique",
        "option4": "It has a definitive end",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a project considered successful? ",
        "option1" : "All deliverables have been completed ",
        "option2": "The phase completion has been approved ",
        "option3": "Stakeholder expectations have been met ",
        "option4": "The customer has provided final payment ",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "You are currently managing multiple projects relating to a high profile build out of a major retail center. The project is extensive, with a two year timeline. Bob is the project manager  responsible for the east block of the build out and Sally is the project manager responsible for the north block of the build out. Both Bob and Sally report to you. Your role can best  be described as:",
        "option1" : "Lead project manager",
        "option2": "Department manager",
        "option3": "Program manager",
        "option4": "Portfolio manager",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following organizational types is the oldest style of organization?",
        "option1" : "Functional organization",
        "option2": "Projectized organization",
        "option3": "Matrix organization",
        "option4": "Balanced matrix organization",
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A project management office (PMO) is responsible for the following activities except:?",
        "option1" : "Measuring project performance and suggesting corrective action",
        "option2": "Assuring efficient use of resources toward a specific business goal",
        "option3": "Evaluating competed project for adherence to project plan",
        "option4": "Maintaining and archiving project documentation for future use",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "During a planning meeting a discussion takes place to decide which resource will be assigned to perform an activity that will be fast tracked. As the project manager you unilaterally decide to assign Fred to the activity. What type of organizational structure is this? ",
        "option1": "Functional organization",
        "option2": "Projectized organization",
        "option3": "Matrix organization",
        "option4": "Balanced matrix organization",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following are process groups except:",
        "option1": "Integration",
        "option2": "Planning",
        "option3": "Executing",
        "option4": "Closing",
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "During which process group are costs the highest? ",
        "option1": "Planning ",
        "option2": "Executing ",
        "option3": "Monitoring and Controlling ",
        "option4": "Closing ",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The concept that each element within a cycle is results oriented and becomes an input  into the next cycle describes which of the following?",
        "option1": "Project management processes",
        "option2": "Phases",
        "option3": "Project life cycle",
        "option4": "Plan Do Check Act cycle",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following statements are true except: ",
        "option1": "It is the  job of the project  manager to ensure that information is explicit, clear, and complete. ",
        "option2": "A project manager must possess a strong knowledge of finance and accounting principles. ",
        "option3": "Organizational and planning skills are an important skill set for a project manager to possess. ",
        "option4": "Power is a technique that the project manager may use to influence people. ",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the level of authority that a project manager has within a functional organization?",
        "option1": "High to ultimate authority",
        "option2": "Authority to assign resources",
        "option3": "Minimal to no authority",
        "option4": "Authority to recommend resources.",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The PMBOK Guide suggests that all projects follow these phases of the project life cycle. Which answer represents the phases of the project life cycle? ",
        "option1": "Planning, Acting, Doing, Checking",
        "option2": "Initiating, Planning, Executing, Monitoring and Controlling, and Closing ",
        "option3": "Discovery, Designing, Execution, and Finishing ",
        "option4": "Initiating, Planning, Performing, and Closing out ",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "General management skills are necessary  foundation for the work of a project manager. Which of the following are  not general management skills a project manager would need?",
        "option1": "Data management skills",
        "option2": "Communication skills",
        "option3": "Conflict management skills",
        "option4": "Budgeting skills",
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What two actions are performed as a part of the Initiating process group?",
        "option1": "Hold  the Project Kickoff Meeting  and Perform Stakeholder Identification",
        "option2": "Develop the Project Charter and Project Kickoff meeting",
        "option3": "Create the Project Plan and Develop the Project Charter",
        "option4": "Develop the Project Charter and Stakeholder Identification",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "What two actions are performed as part of the Closing process group?",
        "option1": "Managing Stakeholder Exceptions and Accepting Project Deliverables",
        "option2": "Managing Stakeholder Exceptions and Closing out  all vendor Contracts",
        "option3": "Finalizing Project work and closing out all vendor contracts",
        "option4": "Finalizing project work and accepting project Deliverables",
        "answer": 3
    }
];
